The Paperboy is a thriller, drama, mystery film directed by Lee Daniels.
A reporter returns to his Florida hometown to
investigate a case involving a death row inmate.
Jack Jansen, played by Zac Efron.
Ward Jansen, played by Matthew McConaughey.
Charlotte Bless, played by Nicole Kidman.
Yardley Acheman, played by David Oyelowo.
Anita / Narrator, played by Macy Gray.
Hillary Van Wetter, played by John Cusack.
The Paperboy is a 2012 American crime drama thriller film co-written and directed by
Lee Daniels and based on Pete Dexter's 1995 novel of the same name.
The novel was inspired by a true story.
It follows Miami reporter Ward Jansen who returns to his hometown in Florida
to investigate a murder case involving a death row inmate.
The film stars Matthew McConaughey, Zac Efron, Nicole
Kidman, David Oyelowo, John Cusack and Macy Gray.
The film was produced by Daniels, Hilary Shor, Avi
Lerner, Ed Cathell III, and Cassian Elwes.
It premiered at the 2012 Cannes Film Festival on May 24,
2012, and October 5, 2012, worldwide.
It grossed $102,706 in its opening weekend and $3.8 million worldwide,
against a budget of $12.5 million, making it a box office bomb.
Despite its mixed reviews, Kidman's performance drew Golden
Globe and Screen Actors Guild Award nominations.
The film explores themes of prison, florida, death row, everglades, swamp.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.